Addison Emery Verrill Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Manuscript Materials, 1864-1926; Series III
  - Mollusca. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Mollusca., 1864-1926; 000946
    - Mollusca. 4 figures of a gastropod. They were found in an envelope labeled by Verrill as "N. Eng Bryozoa notes and sketches and finished figs." These 4 figures were the only things found in envelope., 1864-1926; 001515
    - Mollusca. 7 figures of Limpets., 1864-1926; 001516
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures and plates of bivalves and gastropods used in Verrill's publications in the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Science and the American Journal of Science., 1864-1926; 001530
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures and plates of Mollusca., 1864-1926; 001534
    - Mollusca. Notes and figures of Gastropoda. Labeled by Verrill as "unfinished gastropods.", 1864-1926; 001535
    - Mollusca. Several pages of notes. Appear to deal with Bermuda Mollusca. Probably relating to Verrill and Bush, 1900 paper on the mollusca of Bermuda., 1864-1926; 001537
    - Mollusca. 10 figures of Mollusca., 1864-1926; 001553
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures and notes of Mollusca, mostly bivalves. Labeled by Verrill as "Bivalves shallow water.", 1864-1926; 001554
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Bivalvia and Gastropoda. Labeled by Verrill as "Drawings & Prooffs Shells Bermuda.", 1864-1926; 001632
    - Mollusca. Photographs of Bivalvia and Gastropoda. Found in same folder as IZAR No. 1632., 1864-1926; 001633
    - Mollusca. Handwritten description of Octopus megalops. Apparently Verrill never published the name. See YPM No. 18164., 1864-1926; 001636
    - Mollusca. Notes and sketches of Bivalvia (Tellina, Ostrea, ect.)., 1864-1926; 001637
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of various Mollusca. Labeled by Verrill as "Mollusca figs copied or engraved.", 1864-1926; 001645
    - Mollusca. 7 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper., 1864-1926; 001648
    - Mollusca. 28 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled by Verrill as "Gastropods deep water drawings used.", 1864-1926; 001649
    - Mollusca. 11 figures of Gastropoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cingula etc. 3/4", 1864-1926; 001650
    - Mollusca. 4 figures of Limpets. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Limpets 1/2", 1864-1926; 001651
    - Mollusca. 4 figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Sipho 2/3", 1864-1926; 001652
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "shallow water Mollusks published Gastropods", 1864-1926; 001653
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Mollusca published Gastropods 1/2", 1864-1926; 001654
    - Mollusca. 9 figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cyclostremea etc. Choristes, Natica ", 1864-1926; 001655
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled "Cingula etc. New Drawings", 1864-1926; 001656
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastrpoda. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper. Labeled by Bush as "Cylichna etc. Drawings 1895", 1864-1926; 001657
    - Mollusca. A figure of Cingula castanea. It is a frontal view. It is drawn on the same card as YPM No. 17632., 1864-1926; 001658
    - Mollusca. Mollusca figures., 1864-1926; 001668
    - Mollusca. Several figures of Dentalium. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper., 1864-1926; 001670
    - Mollusca. Several figures of Mollusca. Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper., 1864-1926; 001671
    - Mollusca. Rough copy of some paper on Mollusca (Bela, Mangilia, Dendronotus, Cratena, etc). Most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush paper., 1864-1926; 001779
    - Mollusca. Figure of the beak/buccal mass of Architeuthis. It is from Prof. Worth's specimen., 1870-1880; 001660
    - Mollusca. Mollusca figures used in Verrill, 1873. See Associations tab., 001663
    - Mollusca. 3 figures used in Verrill, A.E. 1882. Trans. Conn. Acad. Arts Sci. 5: 447-588, pl 57, fig. 3-5., 001787
    - Mollusca. 2 plates of Bivalvia figures., 001504
    - Mollusca. A collection of Gastropoda figures, including Crepidula plana., 001505
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures of Gastropoda (Bela, etc.) most likely used in a Verrill and/or Bush publication., 001788
  - Nemertea. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Nemertea., 1864-1926; 000994
    - Nemertea. Rough copy of Verrill manuscripts related to Nemertea. Most are in A.E. Verrill handwriting, some appear transcribed by K.J. Bush. Some rough figures included. The papers were found bound by string., 1864-1926; 000995
    - Nemertea. A figure of a ribbon worm from Hawaii. C.M. Cooke., 1864-1926; 001509
  - Platyhelminthes. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Platyhelminthes., 1864-1926; 001549
    - Platyhelminthes. Several notes and descriptions. Labeled by Verrill as "Turbellaria N. Haven. mostly used in 1st Report.", 1864-1926; 001550
  - Tunicata. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Tunicata., 1864-1926; 001643
    - Tunicata. A plate containing 8 figures of Tunicata. One figure is of a Boltenia. Unknow if used in any publication., 1864-1926; 001644
    - Tunicata. Several figures of Ascidiacea (Cynthia, etc.), 1864-1926; 001666
    - Tunicata. Notes and figures of various Tunicata (Cynthia, Molgula) labeled as "mostly used" by Verrill., 1871; 001786
  - Webster's Dictionary. Archives related to A.E. Verrill's work on the Webster's Dictionary., 1889; 001519
    - Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures of grasses. Also included are 2 lists of grasses and several miscellaneous figures (bird, flowers, fish). Appear to be used in preparation of Verrill's contribution to the Webster's Dictionary., 1889; 001520
    - Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures of miscellaneous organisms (invertebrates, mammals, fish, reptiles, birds, etc.). Most likely used in research for Verrill's dictionary work., 1889; 001659
    - Webster's Dictionary. Figures of fossil brids, mammals, dinosaurs, arachnids, etc., 1889; 001669
    - Webster's Dictionary. Labeled as "Dictionary cuts etc. drawings in proof notes and caption." Possibly non-dictionary related material also, including lists of species, etc., 001560
    - Webster's Dictionary. Numerous figures, labeled by Verrill as "Dictionary cuts", 001642
- Biographical Materials, 1864-1926; Series IV
  Material related to Verrill's life and achievements.
  - Awards. Awards, etc. given to A.E. Verrill., 1864-1926; 001014
    - Awards. Diploma recognizing A.E. Verrill's admittance into the National Academy of Sciences., 17 Apr 1872; 001015
  - Biography. Papers related to A.E. Verrill biography., 1864-1926; 001772
    - Biography. 8 copies of Verrill's advertisement to sell the collections., 1885; 001777
    - Biography. A brief biography about Verrill from 1904., 001773
  - Genealogy. Papers related to Verrill family Genealogy., 1864-1926; 001673
    - Genealogy. Ancestors of George W. Verrill and Lucy Hilborn (2 copies). Ancestors in female lines of George W. Verrill (6 copies). Ancestors of Asa Barton, great grandfather of Flora Louise Smith (6 copies)., 1864-1926; 001674
  - Photographs, Paintings, etc. Photographs of A.E. Verrill, family, etc., 1864-1926; 001603
    - Photographs, Paintings, etc. A painting of A.E. Verrill., 1864-1926; 005917
    - Photographs. A photo negative of A.E. Verrill., 1864-1926; 001604
  - Postcards. Postcards sent to A.E. Verrill., 1864-1926; 001982
    - Postcards. A postcard from E.B. Verrill sent to her father, A.E. Verrill. Digitcal copy only., 1864-1926; 001983
- Research Materials, 1864-1926; Series V
  - Figures. Miscellaneous figures used in A.E. Verrill's research., 1864-1926; 001004
    - Figures. On one side of the sheet are 4 figures of Ascidiacea identified by Verrill as "Perophora?". There are also 3 figures Sipuncula identified as "Sipunculid". One the opposing side are 2 figures, male and female of a the Nematoda, identified as "Pontonema maxima", 1864-1926; 001005
    - Figures. A drawing and description of Leioptilum undulatum, from Gulf of Fonseca. See YPM No. 10467., 1864-1926; 001540
    - Figures. Miscellaneous figures of Cnidaria, Echinodermata, Mollusca, Anneldia, etc., 1864-1926; 001665
  - Notebooks. Miscellaneous notebooks used in Verrill's research., 1864-1926; 001080
    - Notebooks. The notebook is a listing of species from USFC Stmr. Bache stations. It appears to be a comparison of hard and muddy bottoms, possible used by Verrill for publication., 1874-1875; 001081
  - Notes. Miscellaneous notes used in A.E. Verrill's research., 1864-1926; 001623
    - Notes. Found together and labeled by Verrill as notes on Cephalopoda., 1864-1926; 001624
    - Notes. Notes on Crustacea collected by F.H. Bradley. Labeled by Verrill as "Bradley's notes on Crustacea etc. Panama.", 1864-1926; 001640
  - Reference Material. Verrill reference material., 1864-1926; 001336
    - Reference Material. A list of refernces relating to Echinodermata of Chile and Peru., 1864-1926; 001337
    - Reference Material. List of Bermuda planaria published in the Transactions of the Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences. Most are Verrill species., 1901; 001340
    - Reference Material. A list of Gorgonacea synonymies from Kent, 1870., Feb 1870; 001539
    - Reference Material. 2 reference lists for various species of Annelida, Mollusca, Echinodermata, Tunicata, etc., 001778
  - Research Collections. Archives related to collections received by A.E. Verrill for the purpose of research. Some may have been returned and some retained in the YPM collections., 1864-1926; 001096
    - Research Collections. List of Corals received by Verrill for study. Specimens are from the Museum of Comparative Zoology and include speicmens from the U.S. Exploring Expedition, William Stimpson and the Northwest Boundry Survey., 1864-1926; 001098
    - Research Collections. List of Echinoidea received from the Museum of Comparative Zoology. The specimens were collected by A.E. Agassiz aboard the USCS Stmr. Blake., 1877-1879; 001097
  - Specimen Lists., 1864-1926; 001338
    - Specimen Lists. Numerours notes and lists ralated to Mollusca and Radiates. Includes a list from P.P. Carpenter., 1864-1926; 001526
    - Specimen Lists. List of Corals and Echinoderms in Verril's hand. Also in Verrill's hane, the word "Copied" is written across both lists. Numbers may be catalog numbers., 1864-1926; 001339
    - Specimen Lists. List of Crustacea from Bermuda., 1864-1926; 001552
    - Specimen Lists. List of Echinodermata, Bryozoa, Hydroida, etc. Found bound together by string., 1864-1926; 001555
    - Specimen Lists. List of specimens from various localities in the Bay of Fundy and off Nova Scotia., 1864-1926; 001621
    - Specimen Lists. Numerous specimen lists. Most appear to be from Gloucester Fisheries Lots., 1864-1926; 001622
    - Specimen Lists. A list titled "Notes on things from V.N. Edwards". In Verrill's hand. See Invoice Ledger., 1877; 001386
    - Specimen Lists. List of Crustacea sent to A.E. Verrill from Bermuda. The specimens were collected by T.H. Bean., 1905-1906; 001667
    - Specimen Lists. List of Sesarma returned by the Smithsonian. See IZAR No. 1681, 1905-1906; 001684
    - Specimen Lists. A list of Gorgoniidae from Panama. Species names are in Verrill's hand. See Invoice Ledger., 001432
    - Specimen Lists. List of pleistocene fossils, mostly Mollusca, possibly collected by Verrill., 001460
- Bibliographic Materials, 1864-1926; Series VI
  - Bibliographic Materials. Archives related to Verrill's bibliography., 1864-1926; 001775
    - Bibliographic Materials. 4 price lists for various Verrill papers., 1864-1926; 001776